Guide to the Jeanne R. Lowe Papers, circa 1941-1972
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series III. Projects and Research by City, 1943-1972
  - Philadelphia, PA
    - Greater Philadelphia Movement, research, 1958-1959 (Folder 23.14)
    - Housing, research, 1959-1966 (Folder 23.15)
    - Housing Code Enforcement, 1960 (Folder 23.16)
    - Industry, notes and research, 1960-1961 (Folder 23.17)
    - Jobs, notes and research, 1962-1964 (Folder 23.18)
    - "Negroes" and anti-poverty, notes and research, 1958-1966 (Folder 24.1)
    - Old Philadelphia, Development Corporation, publications, 1957-1960 (Folder 24.2)
    - Old Philadelphia, Development Corporation, publications, 1963-1966 (Folder 24.3)
    - Redevelopment, notes and research, 1953-1961 (Folder 24.4)
    - Redevelopment Authority of the City of Philadelphia, "Summary Report of the Central Urban Renewal Area, 1956 (Folder 24.5)
    - Reichley, James, "The Art of Government: Reform and Organization Politics in Philadelphia, 1959 (Folder 24.6)
    - Renewing Renewal, 1959-1966 (Folder 24.7)
    - Schools, notes and research, 1961-1962 (Folders 24.8-24.9)
    - Society Hill and Washington Square East, notes and research, 1957-1960 (Folder 24.10)
    - Traffic and transit, notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folders 24.11-24.12)
    - Transportation, notes and research, 1962-1965 (Folder 24.13)
    - Urban renewal, notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 24.14)
    - West Philly, notes and research, 1962-1966 (Folder 24.15)
  - Pittsburgh, PA
    - ACTION, notebook, undated (Folder 24.16)
    - ACTION-Housing, Inc., 1960-1961 (Folder 24.17)
    - Homewood Community Improvement Association, 1960-1961 (Folder 24.18)
    - Interview notes, 1960-1962 (Folder 25.1)
    - Junior League, "Quality in the Urban Environment," notes and drafts, undated (Folder 25.2)
    - "The New Coalition," drafts, undated (Folder 25.3)
    - "The New Coalition," Hazlett revisions, 1962 (Folder 25.4)
    - New Coalition and conference notes, 1965 (Folder 25.5)
    - Notes and research, 1964-1966 (Folder 25.6)
    - Notes and research, 1965-1966 (Folder 25.7)
    - Research, 1961-1963 (Folder 25.8)
    - Schools, notes and research, 1961-1965 (Folder 25.9)
  - Rochester, NY
    - Committee for Economic Development (CED) Study, correspondence and meeting minutes, 1963-1966 (Folder 25.10)
    - Committee for Economic Development (CED) Study, "The Rochester Bureau of Municipal Research," drafts, 1965 (Folder 25.11)
    - Committee for Economic Development (CED) Study, "The Rochester Bureau of Municipal Research," drafts, 1966 (Folder 25.12)
    - Correspondence, the MacMillan Company, 1967 (Folder 25.13)
    - Drafts, "conclusion", undated (Folder 25.14)
    - Drafts and notes, "The Community Today", circa 1964 (Folder 25.15)
    - Notebooks, 1963 (Folder 25.16)
    - Notebooks, 1964 (Folder 25.17)
    - Notes, "community views of Bureau and Albany", undated (Folder 25.18)
    - Notes and research, 1963-1965 (Folder 25.19)
    - Notes and research, undated (Folder 25.20)
    - Notes and research, Monroe County, 1964-1965 (Folder 26.1)
  - St. Louis, MO
    - Notes and research, 1961 (Folder 26.2)
  - Sunnyvale, CA
    - Correspondence and outline, 1959-1966 (Folder 26.3)
    - Correspondence, finance and development policies, 1958-1959 (Folder 26.4)
    - Drafts - first draft and notes, undated (Folder 26.5)
    - Drafts - "How to Build a New City", 1958-1959 (Folder 26.6)
    - Drafts - "How to Avoid Community Growing Pains", 1959 (Folder 26.7)
    - Drafts - "How to Build a New City", 1963 (Folder 26.8)
    - Drafts - "How to Build a New City", circa 1963 (Folder 26.9)
    - Drafts - "How to Build a New City," first revision, circa 1966 (Folder 26.10)
    - Drafts - "How to Build a New City", undated (Folder 26.11)
    - Drafts - "conclusion", undated (Folder 26.12)
    - Drafts - outline, 1962 (Folder 26.13)
    - Notebooks #1-2, undated (Folder 26.14)
    - Notebooks, undated (Folder 26.15)
    - Notecards, undated (Folder 26.16)
    - Notes and correspondence, "problems", 1961-1962 (Folder 26.17)
    - Notes and drafts, undated (Folder 26.18)
    - Research and notes, undated (Folders 26.19-26.21)
    - Research and notes, undated (Folder 27.1)
    - Research and notes, "early history", 1943-1957 (Folder 27.2)
    - Research and notes, maps and ephemera, 1959 (Folder 27.3)
    - Research and notes, "A Report from KOBE, Inc.", circa 1961 (Folder 27.4)
    - Research and notes, "schools", 1960-1962 (Folder 27.5)
  - Toronto, Canada
    - "A Report on the Metropolitan Toronto System of Government", 1961 Nov (Folder 27.6)
    - Urban development, research, 1953-1961 (Folder 27.7)
- Series IV. Subject Files, 1951-1972
  - ACTION - Notes and research, 1951-1957 (Folder 27.8)
  - Business and urban renewal, notes and research, 1958-1960 (Folder 27.9)
  - California metro, notes and research, 1962 (Folder 27.10)
  - "The Crisis," notes and research, 1968-1970 (Folders 27.11-27.12)
  - "The Crisis," notes, undated (Folder 27.13)
  - European Urban Development - Great Britain, notes and research, 1970 (Folder 27.14)
  - European Urban Development - Israel, research, 1965-1968 (Folder 27.15)
  - European Urban Development - Notebooks, 1970 (Folders 27.16-27.18)
  - European Urban Development - "Report of the International Seminar on Urban Renewal - The Hague", 1958 (Folder 27.19)
  - European Urban Development - Rome, notebooks, undated (Folder 27.20)
  - European Urban Development - Rome and Venice, traffic and city planning, notes and research, undated (Folder 27.21)
  - European Urban Development - Sweden, notes and research, 1970 (Folder 27.22)
  - Highways, correspondence, notes, and research, 1957 (Folders 28.1-28.2)
  - "Industry in Suburbs," notes and research, 1961 (Folder 28.3)
  - "Industry in Suburbs," Fairlawn Industrial Park, notes and research, 1957-1960 (Folder 28.4)
  - Land use and zoning, notes and research, 1969 (Folders 28.5-28.6)
  - Local Government, notes and research, 1957-1959 (Folder 28.7)
  - The MacDowell Colony, 1970-1972 (Folder 28.8)
  - Metropolis, notes and research, 1957, 1960 (Folder 28.9)
  - Metropolis, notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folders 28.10-28.12)
  - Metropolis, notes and research, 1962 (Folder 28.13)
  - "Metropolis Against Itself" by Robert C. Wood, annotated, 1959 Mar (Folder 28.14)
  - "Metro - Other cities," notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 28.15)
  - National Civic Review, annotated, 1960 Apr (Folder 28.16)
  - National Civic Review, annotated, 1961 (Folder 28.17)
  - National Civic Review, annotated, 1962 Mar (Folder 28.18)
  - Nevada industries, Inc., research, 1960-1961 (Folder 28.19)
  - New Jersey planning, notes, 1968-1969 (Folder 28.20)
  - New Jersey planning, research, 1968-1969 (Folders 29.1-29.2)
  - New Jersey planning and Paul Ylvisaker, research, 1968 (Folder 29.3)
  - New Towns, research, 1969 (Folder 29.4)
  - New Towns - Columbia, Maryland, research, 1969 (Folder 29.5)
  - New Towns - Columbia - Reston, VA, 1970 (Folder 29.6)
  - New Towns - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1970 (Folder 29.7)
  - New Towns - London, correspondence, notes, and research, 1970 (Folder 29.8)
  - Property Taxes, notes and research, 1960-1964 (Folder 29.9)
  - Property Taxes, notes and research, 1961 (Folder 29.10)
  - Public Housing, notes, circa 1968 (Folder 29.11)
  - Public Housing, notes, undated (Folder 29.12)
  - Public Housing, notes and research, 1959-1962 (Folder 29.13)
  - Public Housing, notes and research, 1960-1961 (Folder 29.14)
  - Public Housing, notes and research, 1961-1962 (Folder 29.15)
  - Public Housing, research, 1951-1962 (Folder 29.16)
  - Public Housing, research, 1957-1962 (Folder 29.17)
  - Public Housing, research, 1958-1959 (Folders 29.18-29.19)
  - Public Housing, research, 1961 (Folder 29.20)
  - Public Housing - Community Relations Service / Justice Dept, notes and research, 1969-1970 (Folder 29.21)
  - Public Housing - Mid-Income Housing, research, 1957-1960 (Folder 30.1)
  - Public Housing - Mid-Income Housing, research, 1958-1963 (Folder 30.2)
  - Public Housing - Urban housing, notes and research, 1961 (Folder 30.3)
  - Race and housing, notes and research, 1956-1962 (Folder 30.4)
  - Race and housing, notes and research, 1959-1962 (Folder 30.5)
  - Race and housing, research, 1957-1959 (Folder 30.6)
  - Raymond, George, notes and research, 1970-1971 (Folder 30.7)
  - Redevelopers, notes and research, 1960 (Folder 30.8)
  - Regional Plan Association, conference, "The Spreading Metropolis", 1962 (Folder 30.9)
  - Suburbs, notes and research, 1956-1960 (Folder 30.10)
  - Suburbs, notes and research, 1957-1966 (Folder 30.11)
  - Suburbs, notes and research, 1961-1962 (Folders 30.12-30.13)
  - Suburbs - ACTION, correspondence and research, 1955-1956 (Folder 30.14)
  - Suburbs and New Towns, notes and research, 1960-1961 (Folder 30.15)
  - Suffolk County Planning Commission, "Report on Local Government Analysis", 1962 Jan (Folder 30.16)
  - Transit and transportation, research, 1958-1961 (Folder 30.17)
  - Urban curricula - Yale, NYU, Columbia, Vassar, research, 1970 (Folder 30.18)
  - Urban redevelopment, research, 1955-1964 (Folder 30.19)
  - Urban redevelopment, research, 1964 (Folder 30.20)
  - Urban sprawl and open space, research, 1956-1960 (Folder 31.1)
  - Victor Gruen, notebooks, undated (Folders 31.2-31.3)
  - Victor Gruen and others, notebooks, undated (Folder 31.4)
  - Victor Gruen, notes and research, 1954-1961 (Folder 31.5)
  - Victor Gruen, notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 31.6)
  - Victor Gruen - Other cities, notes and research, 1958-1961 (Folder 31.7)
  - Victor Gruen - Vehicles and shopping, notes and research, 1957-1961 (Folder 31.8)
  - Victor Gruen, Rochester, and shopping malls - drafts and notes, 1959 (Folder 31.9)
  - Victor Gruen, Rochester, and shopping malls - drafts and notes, 1960 (Folder 31.10)
  - Victor Gruen, Rochester, and shopping malls - drafts and notes, 1962-1963 (Folder 31.11)
  - Victor Gruen, Rochester, and shopping malls - notes and research, 1958-1963 (Folder 31.12)
  - Victor Gruen, shopping, Ft. Worth - notes and research, 1958-1962 (Folder 31.13)
  - Ylvisaker, Paul N. - speeches, 1961-1969 (Folder 31.14)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes and research, 1951-1956 (Folder 37.4 (Oversize))
  - Miscellaneous - Notes and research, 1957-1962 (Folder 31.15)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes and research, 1958 (Folder 31.16)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes and research, 1958-1965 (Folder 31.17)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes and research, 1961-1962 (Folder 31.18)
  - Miscellaneous - Notes and research, 1962 (Folder 31.19)
- Series V. Jeanne Lowe Research Library, 1948-1972
  - Chicago, IL, 1956-1966 (Box 36)
  - Miami, FL, 1954-1961 (Box 32)
  - New Haven, CT, 1954-1961 (Box 32)
  - New York, NY, 1954-1972 (Boxes 32-33)
  - Philadelphia, PA, 1957-1966 (Box 34)
  - Rochester, NY, 1960-1965 (Box 36)
  - Sunnyvale, CA, 1948-1964 (Boxes 34-35)
  - Washington, D.C., 1961-1964 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1952-1968 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1969-1971 (Box 36)